Jordan Kotsopoulos

Elite 9 Sports Residence, Dubai Sports City, Dubai, UAE +971.52.138.7081 • jpkotsopoulos@hotmail.com

Dual Citizenship: Canadian & Portuguese

Personal Summary

At age 26 I find myself living in Dubai three years after courageously deciding to leave the Canadian finance industry from which I had a stable, lucrative career lined up. I have lived, learned and worked in four culturally different countries (Canada, United States, Spain and UAE), all the while traveling and experiencing many more. If I was to define my personal "super power" I would define it as having the unique ability to foresee the opportunity of collaboration between two or more ideas, businesses or people and identifying how they can gain mutual benefits (opportunity optimizer). I'm an active, rapid learning with intense curiosity, always reading new books or pursing free online courses and masterclasses relating to coding, music, business or progressive learning and personal wellbeing.

Education

Lucation	
MBA Sports Management, La Liga (LFP) – UCAM, Murcia, Spain	Nov. 2015 – Sept. 2016
 Honours BA – Applied Economics, Class of 2015, Wilfrid Laurier University, Waterloo, ON 	Jan. 2012 – Aug. 2015
Soccer for Life (coaching course), Ontario Soccer Association, Canada	Mar. 2014
Financial Modelling in Excel, Financial Modelling Group Inc., Toronto, ON	Mar. 10, 2014
Canadian Securities Course, Canadian Securities Institute, Toronto, ON	Jan. 27, 2014

Previously attended - Cleveland State University, Cleveland, Ohio (*Jan. 2011 – Dec. 2011*) & Northern Kentucky University, Highland Heights, Kentucky (Aug 2010 – Dec 2010)

Work Experience

Business Development, The Royal Emirates Sports Academy, Dubai

Sept. 2016 - Present

- Developed and implemented successfully the Study N' Play scholarship program (4 success stories)
- Developed, managed and made relevant, the Dubai Sports City Football Academy website Increasing average unique pageviews from **3,000 to 6,000** via content creation and management with WordPress, HTML & CSS.
- Project manager, innovative developer and coordinator of Dubai Sports Council Championship (18 Academies, 65 teams, 1500 participants) Football Academy league in partnership with the government authority of sport in Dubai
- Development, management and execution of the U13 Dubai Intercontinental Football Cup(2017 and 2018), hosting world renowned clubs such as Real Madrid, AC Milan and Celta Vigo, FC Barcelona, Juventus, Liverpool and more, coordinating TV broadcasting, marketing, sponsors, finances and logistics
- Developed and managed the first Intercontinental Cup Qualifier in Accra, Ghana with the winning team attending in the Dubai 2018 Intercontinental Cup edition all expenses paid
- Project leader of Green Week Program, international training camps, geared towards creating the Football Academy as a global hub for football development
- SSS football academy coach for U6, U8, U13, U14, working with kids on the development of their skills, and mental performance consistency

Internship, Dubai Sports City Football Academy, Dubai

Jun. 2016 - Jul. 2016

- Business development for Spanish Soccer School programs
- Project planning, financial forecasting and predicting profitability/sustainability of programs
- Coaching Spanish Soccer Kids

- Attended Major League Soccer combine with two prevalent FIFA agents from North America
- Performed daily tasks of organizing and keeping track of meetings with players
- Scouting/recruitment of players for Wilfrid Laurier University Women's soccer team
- Managing operations and coaching elite youth soccer camps

Spot Trading Foreign Exchange, Royal Bank of Canada

May 2014 - Aug. 2014

- Managed \$USD 5 million of risk for personal spot trading portfolio, performing under high levels of pressure
- Designed/Coded VBA excel programs to increase job efficiency and minimize opportunity for errors
- Calculated daily profits/losses then updated global data sheets
- Maintained RBC's Capital markets foreign currency positions by offsetting foreign risk exposure
- Research/data reports on foreign countries economic indicators

Product Management, Sun Life Global Investments,

Summer 2012 & Summer 2013

- Research reports, "Why it's a good time to invest in US/global equity."
- Research reports on fixed income funds & active vs. passive management for prospective clients
- Developed and programmed KYC Questionnaire using excel VBA
- Fund performance updating updated quarterly reports and PowerPoint presentations
- Completed tasks for the product, operations & client service departments

Burlington Soccer Club Coach, Burlington Youth Soccer League (BYSL)

Nov. 2012 - Nov. 2016

- 14 of 18 players of the team currently playing University soccer
 - o 7 of the 14 with athletic scholarship money

Internet Marketing, Edukick Inc. (Global Soccer boarding school)

Jun. 2008 - Jan. 2009

• Updated/recommended enhancements to company websites and prospected potential clients

Computer Proficiencies / Languages

- Knowledgeable in computer coding (VBA & HTML/CSS) and WordPress
 - o Designed & coded personal online resume (HTML & CSS) Click to view website (under development)
 - Designed & coded many VBA projects for *Sun Life Global Investments'* product management team and *Royal Bank of Canada's* foreign exchange spot trading team.
- Photoshop Self-taught, capable and creative
- Proficient in Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint)
- Web Design Created web page sports resume http://jkotsopoulos.blogspot.ca/

.....

- Native English speaker (Born, raised and lived in Canada for most of my life)
- Proficient in conversational Spanish (Spain)
 - o Capable of speaking the language with sufficient structural accuracy and vocabulary to participate effectively in most one on one conversations for practical and social topics.

Achievements & Volunteer Experience

- Successfully initiated and fulfilled a dream of an aspiring street boy from Teshi Mobil, Ghana
- Recognized as young influential Sports Management leader by American University in the Emirates and asked to speak at Sports Conference.
- Won a NCAA Division 2 National Championship with Northern Kentucky University men's varsity soccer program, 2010 (Selected to the NCAA All-Tournament Team)
- Played for and captained Wilfrid Laurier University Men's soccer team 2012 2015
- Selected for first U17 Canadian National team training camp in Montreal, 2008
- National Champion and Captain with Ontario boys U14 provincial soccer program in 2006
- Captain of Ontario Provincial soccer team from 2005-2008 and for the Toronto FC academy team from 2008-2009
- Volunteered as ball boy supervisor for the Toronto FC 2007 to 2009
- Volunteered Christmas 2007 at the Good Sheppard Centre for the homeless in Hamilton, Ontario

ENCOURAGED TO SPEAK WITH REFERENCES